# VASAN ROUTH

# Full Stack Game Developer | Mentor

+918072290237

vasanrouth.github.io

- @ vasanrouth@gmail.com
- Pondicherry,India



## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Game Dev Mentor

#### **Outscal**

苗 06/2024 - Present 👂 New Delhi, India [Remote]

Unity, C++, C#, SFML, Design Patterns

- Coaching students to learn game development, starting from OOPs till building a resume & portfolio,
- Helping them to clear interviews with ease and land jobs in top Game studios,
- Crafting comprehensive courses and coding assignments in C++ and in Unity that fits the student's skill level.

## Lead Game Developer

### Daceg.Ltd

https://about.me/daceg

Unity ,C#, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Moralis SDK, EtherJS, Solidity, Elasticsearch, Unity Cloud Build(CI/CD),

- Lead a team of 5 to build an **MMORTS game** made with Unity (Hosting map servers. Buildings movement, Troop training, Combat mechanics..etc)
- My other work include building a mix of **Card + RTS genre-type mobile game** for both Android and IOS platforms,
- Managed the team using Scrum by breaking down a project into smaller, manageable tickets

## Game Developer

#### **Creatr Studios Inc**

**=** 03/2021 - 06/2022

▼ Toronto, Canada [Remote]

https://www.creatrstudios.ca/

Unity ,C#, GraphQL, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Enjin SDK, Facebook SDK, Azure VM, LeanTween

- Worked on an 8-bit style multiplayer <u>treasure-digging game</u> with multiple modes,
- Collaborated closely with artists and designers to integrate assets and achieve a visually stunning game world,
- Interacted with Enjin cloud using GraphQL queries and mutations, performed safely in the Google Cloud Run (NodeJS) platform,
- Utilized Photon cloud to transmit player inputs through RPC calls keeping the game state in sync, with calls backed up in the cloud to cross verify player actions.

## Game Developer Intern

## **FrostDrakeGames**

**=** 03/2020 - 01/2021

Pondicherry, India

Unity ,C#, NodeJS, Photon Network, Playfab, CloudRun, Facebook SDK, Blender

- Tasked with creating an **turn-based strategy game** built for mobile devices called Gambit, which includes modes like 1v1 skill-based bet matches,
- Developed several server-side components to enable blockchain features,
- Implemented a lot of other modules like a notification system, loot boxes, leaderboard, viewing player profile, Friends... etc,

## Full-Stack Developer

## **IgniteSkylabs**

Attps://www.igniteskylabs.in/

Unity, C#, Vuforia SDK, ARCore, ReactJS, NodeJS, Azure, MongoDB, Python, C#

- Created web and mobile apps for startups and corporations like NCR, GE, HP,
- Developed an Indoor navigation AR mobile application in Unity,
- Worked on other commercial projects including an  $\underline{\textbf{Automobile Tracking App}}$  and **Education Apps**

## **ABOUT ME**

Love coding and playing games | I am a versatile Game Developer with 5+ years of experience, specializing in Multiplayer's. Published multiple games and had the opportunity to lead teams of awesome devs. Part-time Mentoring aspiring students to land jobs in the games industry!

# **SKILLS**

#### **Engines**

Unity (5+ Years), Unreal (1+ Years), Godot (1+ Years)

# Languages

C, C++, C#, JavaScript (ES4-ES2022), Java, Python, HTML, PHP, Solidity

# Cloud/Networking

AWS, Azure, GCM, Firebase, Playfab, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Socket.IO, Photon, Mirror

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics & Communication Engg

#### **Pondicherry University**

Highschool Diploma in Computer Science

## Amalorpavam Hr. Sec. School

# **COURSES/ CERTIFICATIONS**



C and C++ Programming

An advanced course on OOPs and DSA



**AWS Certified Developer Associate** 

Course on using AWS tools and insights of each services.

## PORTFOLIO HIGHLIGHTS

Word Clashers - PvP Word Game

Unity, C#, JS, Playfab, Photon, GCM

Bubble Shooter: Bubble Pop

@ https://shorturl.at/q400J Unity, C#, GPG